RISHI GADHIA

SUMMARY

Rishi is a passionate, self-driven software engineer, currently working as a Solution Analyst at Deloitte. He has around two years of experience in developing and designing large-scale applications across different sectors. He possesses very strong fundamental CS skills and is dedicated to continuous learning.

EDUCATION

University of Central Florida

August 2020 - May 2024

Computer Science B.S.

GPA: 3.4

Relevant Courses: Algorithms for Machine Learning, Discrete Computational Structures, Computer Science II, Artificial Intelligence, Object-Oriented Software Development, Databases, Parallel Computing, Systems Software

EXPERIENCE

Solution Analyst | *Deloitte*

September 2024 – Present

- Modernized legacy systems as a Junior Developer on several large-scale web applications, creating a better experience for millions of users
- Contributed by building the UI/UX, implementing business logic, and fixing critical defects

Full-Stack Developer | University of Central Florida

September 2023 – May 2024

- Participated in a program known as Senior Design, where students were to design and build a realworld application over the course of two semesters
- Extended a previous senior design project to support over 200,000 users by creating CI/CD pipelines, building UI/UX, and fixing core defects.

Sales Associate | *Advanced Data Associates*

June 2021 - July 2021

- Worked during the summer of my freshman year, where I was tasked with handling daily calls and directing customers to products from our business partners.
- I successfully directed a large number of customers and was considered a top salesperson by my boss during this time

Cheer Team Leader | *Empath Health*

July 2018 - March 2020

I led a team to visit and cheer the elderly under an Empath Health volunteering group

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Portfolio Website | TailwindCSS, JavaScript, React, Next.js

- Designed a **responsive** interactive website that displays my accomplishments and goals as a software developer
- Viewable at Rishi Gadhia's Portfolio

Game Review | Express.js, MongoDB, React, Node.js, Android Studio, Kotlin

- Collaborated with a team of six to create a web and native mobile application using the **MERN** stack to allow users to sign up and review their favorite games
- Contributed by writing **REST APIs** and helped build the backend architecture

Money Manager | React Native, TypeScript, Expo

- Collaborated with a team of four to develop an application that allows users to visualize and note their finances
- Built a functioning cross-platform application with a customizable UI and won KnightHacks club competition

SKILLS

Languages: Python, JavaScript, Go, Java, C/C++, Kotlin

Frameworks & Libraries: React, Next.js, TailwindCSS, Express.js, Flask, Spring

Tools: Git, SVN, CI/CD, Docker, Linux, Android Studio, Tmux

Databases: DuckDB, SQLite3, PostgreSQL, MySQL, IBM Db2, Oracle DB, MongoDB, Redis

Certifications: AWS Cloud Practitioner, Kaggle Machine Learning, Git Workflows